<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Dong - A place to track my time log</title>
    <link>https://dongchen.co/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Dong - A place to track my time log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 11:20:55 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dongchen.co/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>22. Bash Shell - Pattern Matching (Globbing Wildcards)</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/22.-bash-shell-pattern-matching-globbing-wildcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 11:20:55 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/22.-bash-shell-pattern-matching-globbing-wildcards/</guid>
      <description>By matching patterns, we can easily find the files we need.
Preparation Let&amp;rsquo;s prepare some test files first before we start:
1  touch 1.txt 2.doc 3.html 1.c 2.c 3.c file1.txt file2.doc file3.html 1file.txt 2file.doc 3file.html   Special Pattern Characters Matches any string We can use the * character to match any string.
Matches any file that starts with file 1  ll file*     Finds any file with filename begin with file   Matches any file that ends with .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21. Pipelines - Get Other Command&#39;s Processed Results as Initial Data</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/21.-pipelines-get-other-commands-results-as-initial-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 07:14:06 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/21.-pipelines-get-other-commands-results-as-initial-data/</guid>
      <description>With the pipe notation, we can pass the output of one program to another as its initial data.
Pipe Notation (|) A Scenario-based Question Let&amp;rsquo;s assume there&amp;rsquo;s a file called fresh_file that holds two lines of text:
1  cat fresh_file     Print fresh_file content   This file has only two lines of text, so the number of lines is noticeable, but what if you encounter a text file with a lot of content?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20. Bash Shell - Redirections</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/20.-bash-shell-reirections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 06:27:53 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/20.-bash-shell-reirections/</guid>
      <description>With the IO redirection feature, we can easily manipulate the input and output of files or other information.
Standard Output The standard output stream is usually used to print the output of a program to a file, its file descriptor is 1.
Output Text to a File 1 2  echo &amp;#39;This is a text for test&amp;#39; &amp;gt; fresh_file cat fresh_file     Output text to fresh_file   Output Result to a File 1 2  ll -a &amp;gt; dir_list_file cat dir_list_file     Output result to fir_list_file   Append Text to a File 1 2  echo &amp;#39;This is a text for test&amp;#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; fresh_file cat fresh_file     Append text to fresh_file   Append Result to a File 1 2  ll -a &amp;gt;&amp;gt; dir_list_file cat dir_list_file     Append result to fir_list_file   Standard Input Standard input streams are usually used to print the contents of a file to a screen, its file descriptor is 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19. Bash Shell - Command Prompt Settings Customization</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/19.-bash-shell-command-prompt-settings-customization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 07:42:28 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/19.-bash-shell-command-prompt-settings-customization/</guid>
      <description>Command Prompt Overview The command prompt looks like the following:
  Command prompt   View Settings of Current Command Prompt There are several ways we can view the settings for the command prompt.
$PS1 Variable We can get the command-line prompt setting by printing the environment variable $PS1:
1  echo $PS1     Command prompt   set Command 1  set | grep PS1     Command prompt   Command Prompt Settings Modification Temporarily Back Up the Original Settings Let&amp;rsquo;s temporarily back up the current command prompt settings:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18. Bash Shell - Directory Stack Builtins</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/18.-bash-shell-directory-stack-builtins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 08:31:14 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/18.-bash-shell-directory-stack-builtins/</guid>
      <description>With a directory stack, we can push the directories we visit sequentially into the directory stack, and when we&amp;rsquo;ve done a series of operations, we can go all the way back to the origin based on the record of the directory stack.
Directory Stack Commands The directory stack provides us with three available commands.
dirs Displays all directories recorded in the directory stack:
1  help dirs     Check dirs&amp;#39;s definition and usage   pushd Records the specified directory to the directory stack and switches the working directory to the recorded directory:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17. Bash Shell - Completion Commands</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/17.-bash-shell-completion-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 07:10:12 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/17.-bash-shell-completion-commands/</guid>
      <description>Most of the time, we can use commands efficiently with the help of Linux&amp;rsquo;s automatic completion capability.
TAB Completion Variable Tab 1  $HISTS # press Tab key to auto-complete this command     before completing     after completing   Command Tab 1  ec # press Tab key to auto-complete this command     before completing     after completing   File Tab 1  # press Tab key to auto-complete this command     before completing     after completing   Possible Completions Can we use Alt+Shift+?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16. Bash Shell - Killing And Yanking</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/16.-bash-shell-killing-and-yanking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 09:35:21 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/16.-bash-shell-killing-and-yanking/</guid>
      <description>You can cut and paste text through the killing and yanking features provided by the bash shell.
Killing Text Forward We can use Ctrl K to cut the text behind the cursor:
1  Ctrl + K # press Control and K keys     before killing     after killing   Killing Text Backward We can use Ctrl U to cut the text before the cursor:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15. Bash Shell - Text Manipulation</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/15.-bash-shell-text-manipulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 08:05:01 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/15.-bash-shell-text-manipulation/</guid>
      <description>We usually need to change the display of some text, and these changes can be made through the text changing command.
Delete char We can use Ctrl + D to delete the character on the current cursor:
1  Ctrl + D # press Control and D keys     before manipulating     after manipulating   Backward delete char We can use Backspace to delete the character before the current cursor:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14. Bash Shell - Cursor Movement</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/14.-bash-shell-cursor-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 07:52:08 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/14.-bash-shell-cursor-movement/</guid>
      <description>We can quickly move the cursor to a specific location with the shortcut key provided by the shell.
Move cursor to the new line We can move the cursor to the beginning of the new line:
1  Ctrl + C # press Control and C keys     before moving     after moving   Move cursor to the beginning We can move the cursor to the beginning of the line:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13. Bourne and Bash Shells&#39; Environment Variables</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/13.-bourne-and-bash-shells-environment-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 08:17:49 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/13.-bourne-and-bash-shells-environment-variables/</guid>
      <description>The shell that Linux used in the first place was Bourne, and then Linux released Bash, which is an enhanced version of Bourne, and most Linux systems now use Bash by default.
Bourne Shell Variables Home and path are the two most commonly used bourne shell variables
HOME Current user&amp;rsquo;s home directory.
1  echo $HOME     prints current user&amp;#39;s home directory   PATH Paths of binary files, which are runnable programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12. Bash Shell History Record Operations</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/12.-bash-shell-commands-history-record-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 07:10:22 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/12.-bash-shell-commands-history-record-usage/</guid>
      <description>With the command reuse feature of the bash shell, it is easy to use a previous command again or to see what commands we have recently used.
  Check history&amp;#39;s definition and usage   History File Location 1  echo $HISTFILE     the file that records the used commands   History Size 1 2  echo $HISTSIZE echo $HISTFILESIZE     these two commands show the amount of the lines of commands they can keep   History List 1  history     shows all recently used commands   Run Previous Command 1  !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11. CentOS 7 - Bash Shell Auto Completion</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/11.-centos-7-bash-shell-auto-completion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 07:13:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/11.-centos-7-bash-shell-auto-completion/</guid>
      <description>CentOS does not install autocompletion support for all tools by default, so we need to install it manually.
Check If We Have Bash Completion Installed We can use the following command to verify:
1  yum list installed | grep completion   We won&amp;rsquo;t see any output if it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been installed, so we need to install this package:
Install 1  yum install bash-completion -y   Although it is installed, it has not yet been loaded into the running bash, so we need to use the source command to load them into the bash:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10. Alias - A Linux Command for Shortcut Creation</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/10.-alias-a-linux-command-for-shortcut-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 07:08:31 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/10.-alias-a-linux-command-for-shortcut-creation/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes a frequently used Linux command can be very long, and when that happens, we need the alias command to help simplify the work of human input.
We can create aliases in two common ways, one for temporary aliases and the other for permanent aliases.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at its help documentation:
1  help alias     Check alias&amp;#39;s definition and usage   We can use the alias command to view the shortcuts owned by current user:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9. Vim - A Powerful Linux Text Editor&#39;s Basic Usage</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/9.-vim-a-powerful-linux-text-editors-basic-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 06:00:30 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/9.-vim-a-powerful-linux-text-editors-basic-usage/</guid>
      <description>Vim Text editor can efficiently help us quickly create or modify some common text type files, such as configuration files:
  Check vim&amp;#39;s definition and usage   Create File 1  vim newfile # After running the command, it&amp;#39;ll create an empty file called newfile     Create a new file   Command Mode Vim opens a file in command mode:
  Command mode   Help We can view the command-related help by the :help command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8. Linux Directory and File Management</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/8.-linux-directory-and-file-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 10:56:58 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/8.-linux-directory-and-file-management/</guid>
      <description>Linux servers exist to process data efficiently, and files store data, so file management is critical. Directories manage files, so directory management is more crucial.
Let&amp;rsquo;s begin with the first one.
Print Current Working Directory Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the manual for the pwd command:
1  man pwd # pwd&amp;#39;s manual     Check pwd&amp;#39;s definition and usage   With this command, we know which directory we are currently working on:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7. Types of Linux Commands</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/7.-types-of-linux-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 06:19:30 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/7.-types-of-linux-commands/</guid>
      <description>Type is a command to view command types. We can look at what types this command can see with the help of the help command:
  there are five types   Alias Alias is a shortcut to commands, such as ll is a simplified version of ls -l:
  the simplified version of ls -l   More&amp;hellip;
Keyword Shell has some reserved keywords, while is one of them:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6. Linux Bash help, System man, info</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/6.-linux-bash-help-system-man-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 07:12:39 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/6.-linux-bash-help-system-man-info/</guid>
      <description>Bash Help Command Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at what bash is, and you can see it through whatis bash, apropos bash or man -k bash commands:
  bash is GNU&amp;#39;s Bourne-Again SHell   The builtins is actually a soft link to bash-builtins:
  builtins is a soft link to bash-builtins   So we can use man builtins, info builtins, man bash-builtins or info bash-builtins commands to view bash&amp;rsquo;s built-in commands:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Linux Command Manual Page (man page)</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/5.-linux-command-manual-page-man-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 07:11:06 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/5.-linux-command-manual-page-man-page/</guid>
      <description>With the power of the man page command, we can see what parameters a command accepts and how to use each parameter corresponding to the command. In this way, we are more efficient when using commands.
Page Sections Given the wide variety of commands, man solves the problem of command classification through section numbering.
1. User Commands Section (1) is used to categorise user commands.
Such as the date command we used earlier:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Linux System and Hardware Times</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/4.-linux-system-and-hardware-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 07:25:20 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/4.-linux-system-and-hardware-times/</guid>
      <description>In a Linux system, we can view the time of the system or the time of the underlying hardware.
Hardware Time We can view the time of the hardware by using the hwclock or clock command. We looked at the two commands separately through the ll command, and we learned that clock was a soft link to hwclock, so they were the same.
With the help of the man command, we know that hwclock is the command used by system administrators:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Linux File Systems</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/3.-linux-file-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 06:41:44 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/3.-linux-file-systems/</guid>
      <description>Filesystem hierarchy standard is maintained by the Linux Foundation, which defines the structure and contents of directories in various distributions of Linux.
  Linux File System on CentOS 7 Distribution   File System Hierarchy File System Hierarchy
Let&amp;rsquo;s look at what each of these directories means and what types of files are suitable for each of them.
bin
Soft link of /usr/bin directory, those are users&amp;rsquo; executable binary files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Linux Installation</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/2.-linux-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 06:22:53 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/2.-linux-installation/</guid>
      <description>In the early days, the operating system could only be installed directly on hardware. As the technology matures, we can implement this in a variety of ways. It can now be installed on virtual machines, in local or cloud containers, or even through the App Store.
Install linux from a local container Docker is a very mature container technology, we can easily access the Linux image of each release by installing docker container technology on Windows and Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. A brief introduction of Linux</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/1.-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 10:45:06 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/1.-introduction/</guid>
      <description>History Because at that time Linus after studying Minix source code discovered that Minix&amp;rsquo;s design is terrible. So he wrote a kernel from scratch, the Linux kernel, based on the assembly and c language he had accumulated as a child. It was later used by many kernel enthusiasts and vendors to develop release versions suitable for their preferences and needs.
C language is a high-level language, its efficiency is much faster than most of the current high-level languages, but the effectiveness of c language is 30% slower than assembly language.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>