<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Dong - A place to track my time log</title>
    <link>https://dongchen.co/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Dong - A place to track my time log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 07:25:20 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dongchen.co/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Linux System and Hardware Times</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/4.-linux-system-and-hardware-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 07:25:20 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/4.-linux-system-and-hardware-times/</guid>
      <description>In a Linux system, we can view the time of the system or the time of the underlying hardware.
Hardware Time We can view the time of the hardware by using the hwclock or clock command. We looked at the two commands separately through the ll command, and we learned that clock was a soft link to hwclock, so they were the same.
With the help of the man command, we know that hwclock is the command used by system administrators:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. File Systems</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/3.-file-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 06:41:44 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/3.-file-systems/</guid>
      <description>Filesystem hierarchy standard is maintained by the Linux Foundation, which defines the structure and contents of directories in various distributions of Linux.
  Linux File System on CentOS 7 Distribution   File System Hierarchy File System Hierarchy
Let&amp;rsquo;s look at what each of these directories means and what types of files are suitable for each of them.
bin
Soft link of /usr/bin directory, those are users&amp;rsquo; executable binary files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Linux Installation</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/2.-linux-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 06:22:53 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/2.-linux-installation/</guid>
      <description>In the early days, the operating system could only be installed directly on hardware. As the technology matures, we can implement this in a variety of ways. It can now be installed on virtual machines, in local or cloud containers, or even through the App Store.
Install linux from a local container Docker is a very mature container technology, we can easily access the Linux image of each release by installing docker container technology on Windows and Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. A brief introduction of Linux</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/1.-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 10:45:06 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/linux/simple-but-profound/1.-introduction/</guid>
      <description>History Because at that time Linus after studying Minix source code discovered that Minix&amp;rsquo;s design is terrible. So he wrote a kernel from scratch, the Linux kernel, based on the assembly and c language he had accumulated as a child. It was later used by many kernel enthusiasts and vendors to develop release versions suitable for their preferences and needs.
C language is a high-level language, its efficiency is much faster than most of the current high-level languages, but the effectiveness of c language is 30% slower than assembly language.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>