<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Dong - A place to track my time log</title>
    <link>https://dongchen.co/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Dong - A place to track my time log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 07:01:23 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dongchen.co/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How did I pass the Zend PHP7 Certified Engineer exam</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/certification/zend-php7-certified-engineer-passing-technique-sharing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 07:01:23 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/certification/zend-php7-certified-engineer-passing-technique-sharing/</guid>
      <description>The other day I received an email from a fellow, which he sent me through Zend&amp;rsquo;s list of certifiers. Although we didn&amp;rsquo;t know each other until then, I felt that since we were all in the community of PHP, I should help him sort out the areas he needed to pay attention to before taking the exam. However, it would be nice if other people who had to prepare for the ZCE PHP7 also found this article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. An overview of the default nginx.conf file</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/nginx/simple-but-profound/4.-default-nginx.conf-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:49:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/nginx/simple-but-profound/4.-default-nginx.conf-file/</guid>
      <description>The first place we need to visit after the installation should be the nginx.conf file. This file contains everything we need for rendering a very basic static HTML web page on HTTP port 80.
If you have started your Nginx process after the installation then we can get its configuration file through the master process:
1  ps -ef | grep nginx   The result should look like:
  Nginx Process   We See the nginx.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Install Nginx</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/nginx/simple-but-profound/2.-install-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:50:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/nginx/simple-but-profound/2.-install-nginx/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. An Introduction</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/nginx/simple-but-profound/1.-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:49:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/nginx/simple-but-profound/1.-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Many companies start on a shoestring budget at first, so they choose Cheap Hosting Plans. However, as they are growing bigger and bigger, their customers are also growing. The next most significant consideration is their portals’ PERFORMANCE.
Most Hosting Plans use Apache Server, it suits well for little traffic websites, but it is a nightmare for high traffic websites, that’s why Nginx was born. People then start moving their websites to Dedicated Virtual Servers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>