<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nginx on Dong - A place to track my time log</title>
    <link>https://dongchen.co/tags/nginx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nginx on Dong - A place to track my time log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 07:51:02 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dongchen.co/tags/nginx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Nginx Space and Time Measurement Units</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/nginx/simple-but-profound/5.-nginx-space-and-time-measurement-units/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 07:51:02 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/nginx/simple-but-profound/5.-nginx-space-and-time-measurement-units/</guid>
      <description>A unit of measurement that is often misleading I often see people confuse the time and space units of Nginx, which is especially prevalent among beginners. One measure unit that most often misleads them is an m letter, which can be expressed either as megabytes or as minutes.
Space Measurement Units Bytes 1  1024 # A unit without a suffix letter stands for bytes.   Kilobytes 1  8k # A unit with a suffix letter &amp;#39;k&amp;#39; or &amp;#39;K&amp;#39; stands for kilobytes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. An overview of the default nginx.conf file</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/nginx/simple-but-profound/4.-default-nginx.conf-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/nginx/simple-but-profound/4.-default-nginx.conf-file/</guid>
      <description>Have a glance of Nginx default configuration file The first place we need to visit after the installation should be the nginx.conf file. This file contains everything we need for rendering a very basic static HTML web page on HTTP port 80.
Locate it through the main process If you have started your Nginx process after the installation then we can get its configuration file through the master process:
1  ps -ef | grep nginx   The result should look like:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Basic Nginx operations</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/nginx/simple-but-profound/3.-basic-nginx-operations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:52:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/nginx/simple-but-profound/3.-basic-nginx-operations/</guid>
      <description>Parameters and Signals Like any other servers, Nginx has its operational instructions (parameters and signals).
The existence of these instructions makes it very convenient for us to manipulate the various configurations of Nginx. We can manipulate Nginx’s status, running path, test configuration files, etc. We can also reload Nginx’s configuration file at its runtime; this feature is handy for minor changes to Nginx while it&amp;rsquo;s running.
1. Parameters Parameters can be used to manipulate Nginx to accomplish some basic tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Install Nginx</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/nginx/simple-but-profound/2.-install-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:50:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/nginx/simple-but-profound/2.-install-nginx/</guid>
      <description>Ways to install Nginx on CentOS 7 Before we begin our journey, we must prepare a CentOS 7 Linux Server, if you don&amp;rsquo;t have one, you can consider getting one from Linode for very cheap price. Or you can follow along with your existing CentOS 7 Linux Server if you have one. If you are ready, then let’s begin our High-Performance Journey!
There are two ways of installation:
1. Nginx package installation This option is suggested to the newcomers since they don&amp;rsquo;t know much details about what exactly Nginx use for, so the first thing they need to do is to quickly install it and start playing around with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. A brief introduction</title>
      <link>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/nginx/simple-but-profound/1.-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:49:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dongchen.co/post/server-side-programming/nginx/simple-but-profound/1.-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Many companies start on a shoestring budget at first, so they choose Cheap Hosting Plans. However, as they are growing bigger and bigger, their customers are also growing. The next most significant consideration is their portals’ PERFORMANCE.
Most Hosting Plans use Apache Server, it suits well for little traffic websites, but it is a nightmare for high traffic websites, that’s why Nginx was born. People then start moving their websites to Dedicated Virtual Servers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>